[Music]
[Música]
Hello my dear friends, how are
muy buenas mis queridos amigos qué tal
you? I hope you're enjoying
estáis Espero que estéis disfrutando de
the afternoon, and even more so. You're going to do it
la tarde y más que lo Vais a hacer
when you see this video that I'm bringing you, which
cuando veáis este vídeo que os traigo
is wonderful. Brave Isabel,
que es una maravilla bravísima Isabel
brave Federico, a round of applause for my
bravísimo Federico un aplauso a mi
show, my favorite radio show. Of
programa mi programa favorito de radio
course, they are excellent, and
Claro que sí es que son excelentes y
what a downpour the paloma Barrientos has had today.
vaya lluvia de sasca se ha comido hoy la
This one, I don't
paloma Barrientos esta que yo ni
even know why she sits on this
siquiera sé porque se sienta en este
show with that thought, the
programa con ese pensamiento a los
TV factory that drives me, I mean,
fábrica de la tele que me lleva o sea
incredible, pay attention everyone, because
increíble atentos todos porque es que
this is just simply impossible to understand. Sit down,
esto no hay por dónde cogerlo sentarse
grab some popcorn, and enjoy different
[__] palomitas y disfrutar diferentes
photos. On the one hand, readings, he's surprised
fotos por un lado lecturas se sorprende
that Antonio David lives off of what he
de que Antonio David viva de las dice lo
calls his fans' donations. This is
llama Los donativos de sus fans Este es
the topic we've been talking about today,
el tema que hemos estado hablando hoy
incredibly regrettable, incredibly
increíblemente lamentable increíblemente
regrettable. I already made an
lamentable ya os hice un vídeo
ironic video, of course ironic, it's called
irónico por supuesto irónico se llama
readings, and Sálvame, they live off their
lecturas y sálvame viven de su
donations, they live off the donations of
donaciones viven de las donaciones de
their followers, and you can see it, I mean, they're
sus seguidores y podéis verlo o sea son
micropayments that everyone can make
micropagos que todo el mundo puede hacer
at work, it's an extra service, it's
en su trabajo es un servicio extra es
an extra option, you can  do it whoever
una opción extra lo puede hacer quien
wants and whoever gets angry can get going
quiera y a quien le dé rabia que se
okay because they have even less shame
arranque vale porque más poca vergüenza
putting in their programs
tienen ellos poniendo en sus programas
that we have to vote spending money
que haya que votar gastándose el dinero
on the messages and in the lines Okay
en los mensajitos y en las líneas Ok
let's
estamos
see these are incomes that you can make
a ver son ingresos que tú puedes hacer
voluntarily from YouTube it's like
de manera voluntaria de YouTube es como
paying for the lecturas magazine you want to
pagar la revista lecturas tú quieres
buy the lecturas magazine you go to the
comprar la revista lecturas vas al
kiosk you pay for it and you take it you know no
kiosco lo pagas y te la llevas sabes no
Federico it's even worse or rather worse for
Federico es peor todavía o sea peor para
that okay you have to buy the lecturas magazine
ello vale tú la revista lecturas la
Yes or yes you
tienes que comprar Sí o sí tú los vídeos
can watch my videos on YouTube
míos de YouTube los puedes ver
completely free you can enjoy them
completamente gratis lo puedes disfrutar
I make the content for all the people
yo hago el contenido para toda la gente
who support me
que me apoya
and now whoever considers it and it doesn't cost
y ahora ya quien considere y no le
anything to spend a euro a month
suponga nada gastarse un euro al mes se
can become a member whoever wants who
pueda ser miembro quien quiera quien
values ​​my product and whoever wants me to
valore mi producto y quien quiere que yo
continue here for many years by the way you
siga aquí por muchos años por cierto
have the link in the first line of
tenéis el enlace en la primera línea de
the description okay in case you
la descripción vale
want okay whoever wants me to
por si queréis vale quien quiera que yo
be here for many years and doesn't mind
esté aquí muchos años y no le importe
spending 99 cents a month can give it
gastarse 99 céntimos al mes le puede dar
But whoever can't because they don't want to or
Pero el que no pueda porque no quiera o
because they can't It's okay you can
porque no pueda No pasa nada puede
continue enjoying the content of the
seguir Disfrutando del contenido de los
live shows  and everything and if a Loli
directos y de todo y si viene una Loli
Huerta Loli comes I send you a huge kiss and
Huerta Loli Te mando un beso enorme y
drops 100 turkey with all her grapefruit
suelta 100 pavo con todo su pomelo
Because she feels like it and she feels like it
Porque le da la gana y le apetece
Welcome be welcome be it because you
Bienvenido sea bienvenidos sea porque
are valuing the work of the people and
estás valorando el trabajo de la gente y
whoever can't can still entertain themselves
quien no pueda se puede entretener
and belong to our
igualmente y pertenecer a nuestra
family
familia
because here we are a family not them who
porque aquí somos una familia no ellos
are sellouts
que son unos vendidos
we
nosotros
natives Of course
nativos Claro
today the lady the lady please then
hoy la señora la señora porfa luego
you have to declare it she doesn't know what she gets
tienes que declararlo no sabe que pega
for epo Of course you have to declare it my
por epo Claro que hay que declararlo mi
soul Look I'm going to tell you one thing
alma Mira te voy a decir una cosa
precisely
precisamente
precisely the work of the youtubers
precisamente el trabajo de los youtubers
is the most transparent that can
es el más transparente que te puede
show you here you don't get away with anything
echar la cara aquí no te libras de nada
because because you collect everything by
porque porque todo lo cobras por
transfers income and things like that and on
transferencias ingresos y cosas así y
top of that you are collecting it in public or
encima lo estás cobrando en público o
so it's clearer than that clarinet yes it
sea más claro que eso clarinete sí que
is true that YouTube takes the
es verdad que YouTube se lleva la se
takes a part or so look at
lleva una parte o sea fíjate tú a
you what comes to us from what we
nosotros lo que nos llega de lo que
generate is really worth of what
generamos en realidad vale de lo que
we generate on YouTube there
nosotros generamos en YouTube ahí se
everything adds up eh or so in plan the
suma todo eh o sea en plan la
monetization the Super The Super
monetización la Los Super Los Super
chats that are called super chat Thank you and
chats que se llaman super chat Gracias y
the members  all that money I had,
los miembros todo ese dinero yo tuve
take 55%.  or in other words, he keeps more than
coge el 55%. o sea se queda más que
we say what's left and he gives us the rest,
nosotros dice lo queda y el resto nos lo
okay? And beyond what we
da vale Y allá de lo que a nosotros nos
get, we have to take, he makes the
llega tenemos que [__] hace la
invoice and the Treasury comes and takes it from you.
facturita y viene Hacienda y te quita
Well, in Taco too, okay, so in the
Pues en Taco también Vale entonces al
end between that and me and something else. Well,
final entre eso y yo y otra cosa Bueno
in the end, they give away more than anything, but
pues al final regalan más que nada pero
well, in life, it's not the life of the
bueno en la vida no es la vida del
worker so that later they cry because they
currante para que luego lloren porque
give us super chats,
nos dan super chats
money.
dinero
Here he is telling her the opposite,
Aquí le está diciendo lo contrario por
please, you are looking for hair, the
favor que estás buscándole el pelo la
chicken's leg, because the
pata a la gallina pues lo declara el
poor man declares it, then,
pobre hombre luego
well, what is
bueno
the woman talking about? That
de que está hablando la mujer de que
until now she will not declare it.
hasta ahora no lo declarará
But what is that lady talking about? I
Pero qué está hablando esa señora es que
am not understanding what she is
no lo estoy entendiendo que lo que está
talking about then I was like, how is she not going to
hablando entonces yo era cómo no lo va a
declare it, girl,
declarar chiquilla
and she had some
y tenía unos contratos
YouTube contracts and with declaring the income of a
YouTube y con declarar los ingresos de
YouTuber, Lady, get yourself
youtuber Señora ubíquese
located, get yourself located, I am going to put it in the thumbnail,
ubiquese lo voy a poner en la miniatura
lady, get yourself located,
señora ubíquese
what does
qué tiene que ver
the Telecinco dismissal sentence have to do with it,
la sentencia de despido de telecinco
absolutely
absolutamente
something else, I don't like that, but here I do
otra cosa eso no me gusta pero que aquí
not understand why she brought up the fact that
no entiendo por qué ha sacado a colación
Olga
lo de Olga
has not paid  the treasury at certain
no ha pagado hacienda en determinados
times and then
momentos y luego sus colaboraciones se
Olga signed her collaborations and that's why
las hacía la firmaba Olga y que por eso
Olga is going to have But there could be, let's see, let's
Olga va a tener Pero puede haber a ver a
see
ver
as far as I know, what happened with Antonio David, the
hasta donde yo sé lo de Antonio David
Treasury was because I could be wrong,
Hacienda era porque me puedo equivocar
eh, I'm speaking from memory, but I think
eh os hablo de memoria pero yo creo que
the thing that the collaborators had
el rollo que tenían los colaboradores
with the Treasury issue was that at first they
con el tema Hacienda es que primero se
could do it, they could pay taxes as
podían hacer se podían tributar como
companies, but then there came a time when the
sociedades pero luego llegó un momento
Treasury said no way, they
en el que Hacienda dijo que nanay que
had to do it. As self-employed, some people
tenían que hacerlo Como autónomo algunos
come out like that, they didn't go and it happened to almost
sale así fue no ir y le pasó a casi
everyone, no, and they had to pay for it,
todos no y tuvieron que ir pagándolo
but the issue of the company from
pero lo del tema de la sociedad desde
Olga comes from the issue of
Olga viene por el rollo de la denuncia
Rocío Carrasco's complaint about the children, no, I mean,
de Rocío Carrasco de los niños no o sea
we're mixing things up because she doesn't know
estamos mezclando cosas porque no sabe
where I came from. But why do you sit her
por dónde salí Pero por qué la sentáis
there, give her a little chair in the courtyard and whatnot, and let her
ahí ponerle una butaquita en el patio y
say her nonsense there,
que y que diga allí su chorrada por
please look, we can't now either, but
favor fíjate tampoco podemos ahora pero
Olga is out, that they told her on
que Olga está fuera que le han dicho en
your program where you work, Ana
tu programa en donde tú trabajas Ana
Rosa, that Olga is out, that Olga no longer
Rosa que Olga está fuera que Olga ya no
has to do with it, that
tiene que ver que el marrón lo tiene
Antonio David is in charge
Antonio David
Lady Have something
señora Tómese algo
good Let's go ahead
bueno Vamos adelante
if we are criticizing the cover of
si estamos criticando la portada de
reading and the sensationalist headline and
lectura y el titular amarillista y
also false I will admit that then in
además falso voy a admitir que luego en
parents great that then it turns out to be a
padres estupendo que luego resulta
risk
riesgo
Lady What has Antonio David done to you I don't
señora Qué le ha hecho Antonio David no
think he would take away your sandwich when
creo que le quitara el bocadillo cuando
you were at school Lady
usted estuviera en el colegio señora por
why so much hatred Telecinco well I say Well come on let's let's
qué tanta inquina telecinco pues digo
also say that there is a part that attacks him
también que hay una parte que le ataca
like it could be that the lecturas magazine
como puede ser la revista lecturas
has marked that line of harassment to this
haya marcado esa línea de acoso a este
man that I personally don't
señor que a mí particularmente no le
know You're welcome Of
conozco De nada
course I do
Claro
n't agree or whatever you
que no estoy de acuerdo o lo que sea me
understand I mean I like him as a
entendéis O sea me gusta como personaje
controversial character pim pam then there are things
polémico pim pam luego hay cosas en los
that I don't agree with him it's
que no estoy de acuerdo con él no pasa
okay but in what the television factory has done
nada pero en lo que ha hecho la fábrica
the whole documentary river I
de la tele todo el río documental yo
think that there we agree almost
creo que ahí estamos de acuerdo casi
all of Spain no well these people except the
todo España no bueno esta gente menos la
carrasquita but a room
carrasquita pero una habitación
absolutely none
absolutamente ninguno
save me you were going to hallucinate because people like
sálvame ibas alucinar porque gente como
María
María testimonio
direct testimony in a program now has
directo en un programa ahora se ha
become well
convertido bueno
Never absolutely no indication
Nunca absolutamente ninguna indicación
and he has put me here another second part and
y me ha puesto aquí otra segunda parte y
with this I am freaking out it is family
yo con esto estoy flipando es familia
Poor thing they say that now it is for the
Pobrecita esta dicen que ahora es por la
mother before it was the suits, that is to say
madre antes eran los trajes es decir
when it is an outrage to reason and to
cuando es un atropello a la razón y a
anything be it Antonio David be it
cualquier cosa sea Antonio David sea
Perico el de los palotes As soon as I
Perico el de los palotes Yo en cuanto
see a series of thugs who change their
veo a una serie de matones que cambian
minds and before she was a bad mother
de opinión y antes era mala madre
extensive before she was charming now it's
extensa antes era encantador ahora es
disgusting then I get angry
asqueroso pues me cabreo
to indicate that she complains eye eye to
para indicar que ella queja ojo ojo a
Isabel here eh eye here I think 10
Isabel aquí eh ojo a aquí creo que 10
minutes
minutos
from home, that is, abandonment of her duties
del hogar o sea abandono de sus tareas
as a mother the prosecutor's office is asking for
como madre la fiscalía le está pidiendo
rociíto I don't know if it's a one-year sentence I
rociíto No sé si es una pena de un año
think that's what we talked about No this
creo que fue lo que hablamos No esta
news came out in the newspapers not in
noticia salió en los periódicos no en
several in fact and we haven't heard
varios de hecho y no hemos escuchado
absolutely a minute on Telecinco
absolutamente ni un minuto en telecinco
of this news how can you not give this
de esta noticia como no podéis dar esta
news how do you think this news
noticia como os parece que esta noticia
is not relevant
no es relevante
we are dedicating minutes to
estamos dedicándole minutos al super
Kiko Rivera's super chat of 20 euros
chat de Kiko Rivera de 20 euritos
Antonio David And we are going to give that
Antonio David Y nos vamos a dar esa
news How good that you want to
noticia Que bueno que la queréis
defend her that you want to justify her that you
defender que la queréis justificar que
want to ignore it but give the
lo queréis pasar por lo alto pero da las
news is that with that they are
noticias es que con eso están
demonstrating not impartiality but
demostrando no la imparcialidad sino el
flattery to Rocío Carrasco and Fidel the
peloteo a Rocío Carrasco y a Fidel el
positioning  and hiding the things
posicionamiento y el ocultar Las cosas
that harm her, that is, with that they
que le perjudiquen o sea es que con eso
are showing you that they are not a means
te están demostrando que no son un medio
of communication, we here give
de comunicación nosotros aquí damos
all the news, all positive or
todas las noticias todas positivas o
negative for whichever side it is, but the fact is that
negativas para el bando que sea pero es
they have not given the news about Rocío Carrasco
que ellos esa noticia de Rocío Carrasco
and the abandonment, the alleged
y el abandono el presunto supuesto
abandonment of the family, they have not given the
abandono de familia no han dado la
news when they are giving it in all the
noticia cuando la están dando en todos
digital media
los medios digitales
and that has not been explained. I have not seen
y eso no se ha explicado Yo no he visto
a single minute,
un solo minutos
a brave thing, Isabel, brave, that someone gives
una cosa brava Isabel brava que alguien
this woman a rum and coke
le ponga un cubata a esta mujer ahora
right now, but it was also very clear, because
mismo pero estaba clarísimo también pues
if not, you do not consider that it is
si no eso no consideras que
actually being manipulated, do not
efectivamente se está manipulando no lo
watch it because then we all feed
veas porque luego nos alimentamos todos
on this story, you
de esta historia
just overlooked it, too, okay,
lo acaba de pasar por alto también vale
if you have noticed, you are not interested, you have to
si os habéis dado cuenta No le interesa
see it to get vaccinated
hay que verlo para vacunarse
from the news and I am telling you
de las noticias y yo te estoy diciendo
what lecturas is telling and I insist,
lo que está contando lecturas e insisto
not only this, not only that headline
ya no solo esto ya no solo ese titular
about life because the lecturas magazine has not
de vida porque la revista lecturas no ha
put the alleged
sacado de portada hoy lo de el presunto
abandonment of home on the cover today, it
abandono de hogar
was not powerful enough. That
no era suficiente potente Esa esa
news for a cover. Today it was the
noticia para una portada Hoy era la
cover, it was the cover, family and  They haven't released it, it's
portada era la portada familia y no la
incredible, I'll be reading you,
esta increíble os estaré leyendo de
really, I've gone dark, eh, I'm going to have a
verdad me he puesto negro eh Me voy a
drink because I've gone dark, give your
tomarme algo porque me he puesto negro
opinion on what you see
opina lo que veáis
[Music]
[Música]